Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.1.3.2
  - Subject Files: Miscellaneous photographs, circa 1917 - 1919; 2 (Box 1514)
    - Verso: Samuel Woodfill whom Pershing called "the greatest American soldier of the war.", 7-verso
    - Caption: With best wishes to my Colorado hostess from her friend, an old Sourdough Capt. Samuel Woodfill U.S. Army Retired July 15, 1928., 8
    - Sergeant and Mrs. Woodfill, 9
    - Verso: Sergeant and Mrs. Woodfill, 9-verso
    - Webb Waldron, editor of Colliers who accompanied an American, Mr. Thomas, and Arch Deacon Nice head of the American Episcopal Church in Germany who worked in American prison camps thru work. Ambassador Gerard speaks highly of him in his books., 10
    - Verso: Webb Waldron, editor of Colliers who accompanied an American, Mr. Thomas, and Arch Deacon Nice head of the American Episcopal Church in Germany who worked in American prison camps thru work. Ambassador Gerard speaks highly of him in his books., 10-verso
    - Left to right: Lieut. Oakley Parkhill and First Sergt. Robert H. Gibson, Company E, Sixty-first Regiment Infantry. Near Cunel, Meuse, France. October 30, 1918, 11
    - Verso: Left to right: Lieut. Oakley Parkhill and First Sergt. Robert H. Gibson, Company E, Sixty-first Regiment Infantry. Near Cunel, Meuse, France. October 30, 1918, 11-verso
    - Joe Dawson, 12
    - Verso: Joe Dawson, 12-verso
    - Southern Sweden; Blue sky with clouds make a beautiful sunset with reflections not too bloody land of windmills and castles, 13
    - Verso: Southern Sweden; Blue sky with clouds make a beautiful sunset with reflections not too bloody land of windmills and castles, 13-verso
    - Woodfill seated in center of group, 14
    - Verso: Woodfill seated in center of group, 14-verso
    - [Man standing in front of automobile], 15
    - [Man hiking up a snowy mountain], 16
    - [Two soldiers (?) standing in an open field], 17
    - [Rocky island], 18
    - [Elaborate head-gear], 19
    - [Portrait of an official-looking man], 20
    - [Two men with canes standing in front of a statue], 21
    - [U.S. Military man], 22
    - Sea of Nature made camel saddles, 23
    - Verso: Sea of Nature made camel saddles, 23-verso
    - [Man in hat], 24
    - [Bust of a man], 25
    - ["Lawrence" bust], 26
    - Major William E. Marshall, Scottish M.D. class, friend of T. E. Lawrence, 27
    - Note: Major William E. Marshall, Scottish M.D. class, friend of T. E. Lawrence, 28
  - Subject files: Miscellaneous photographs, circa 1917 - 1919; 3 (Box 1514)
    - Chauval, 1
    - Verso: Chauval, 1-verso
    - Lord Calthorpe, admiral in command the British and French Mediterranean fleets and the present governor of Constantinople, 2
    - Verso: Lord Calthorpe, admiral in command the British and French Mediterranean fleets and the present governor of Constantinople, 2-verso
    - Alban-Studio, Rue Rosette 13, Alexandrie, 3
    - Verso: Alban-Studio, Rue Rosette 13, Alexandrie, 3-verso
    - DC Hogarth, 4
    - Verso: DC Hogarth, 4-verso
    - DC Hogarth, 5
    - Verso: DC Hogarth, 5-verso
    - Checkoslovak officers in Fiume, 6
    - Verso: Checkoslovak officers in Fiume, 6-verso
    - Col. Edward Davis, Amer. Cavalry, 7
    - Verso: Col. Edward Davis, Amer. Cavalry, 7-verso
    - Spoils from the Western front; Harry Chase wearing German helmet on Armistice day, 8
    - Verso: Spoils from the Western front; Harry Chase wearing German helmet on Armistice day, 8-verso
    - [Ship captain (?)], 9
    - [Ship captain (?)], 10
    - [Ship captain (?)], 11
    - [Two fencers on horses], 12
    - [Four men and a cow standing in front of an airplane, 13
    - [Three people standing outside "Y.W.C.A." building], 14
    - [Silhouette of a man], 15
    - [Busy town street], 16
    - [Ship captain (?)], 17
    - [Trolley tracks running through a square], 18
  - Subject files: Miscellaneous photographs, circa 1917 - 1919; 4 (Box 1514)
    - Beirut - a miss, 1
    - Verso: Beirut - a miss, 1-verso
    - Beirut - hit by 65 lb. bomb, 2
    - Verso: Beirut - hit by 65 lb. bomb, 2-verso
    - Docks at Beirut after direct hit with one 65 lb. bomb, 3
    - Verso: Docks at Beirut after direct hit with one 65 lb. bomb, 3-verso
    - French and American flags; French sentry in middle dressed in horizon blue; held by A.E.F. Censor, 8 NOV 1917, 4
    - Verso: French and American flags; French sentry in middle dressed in horizon blue; held by A.E.F. Censor, 8 NOV 1917, 4-verso
    - 2 American soldiers in kaiki [sic]. Frenchman in horizon blue. White stone bridge. Dark green railing. Red tile roof on white tower; held by A.E.F. Censor, 8 NOV 1917, 5
    - Verso: 2 American soldiers in kaiki [sic]. Frenchman in horizon blue. White stone bridge. Dark green railing. Red tile roof on white tower; held by A.E.F. Censor, 8 NOV 1917, 5-verso
    - Rough pine barracks with tar paper roof; held by A.E.F. Censor, 8 NOV 1917, 6
    - Verso: Rough pine barracks with tar paper roof; held by A.E.F. Censor, 8 NOV 1917, 6-verso
    - held by A.E.F. Censor, 8 NOV 1917, 7
    - Verso: held by A.E.F. Censor, 8 NOV 1917, 7-verso
    - Kakai [sic] uniforms, 8
    - Verso: Kakai [sic] uniforms, 8-verso
    - The spot on the Jerusalem [?] cross road showing the white flag flying; Dec 9th 1917, 9
    - Verso: The spot on the Jerusalem [?] cross road showing the white flag flying; Dec 9th 1917, 9-verso
    - Jerusalem; 9.12.17 (mounted photograph), 10
    - 9.12.17 (mounted photograph), 11
    - Dugout - Sinai Desert, 12
    - Verso: Dugout - Sinai Desert, 12-verso
    - Oasis and British gun emplacement in Sinai Desert, 13
    - Verso: Oasis and British gun emplacement in Sinai Desert, 13-verso
    - War 1914-17 A clean shave 27-9-17; A.F. Randon [?], 14
    - Verso: War 1914-17 A clean shave 27-9-17; A.F. Randon [?], 14-verso
    - War 1914-17 A greatful French but soon to be American soldier 27-9-17; A.F. Randon [?], 15
    - Verso: War 1914-17 A greatful French but soon to be American soldier 27-9-17; A.F. Randon [?], 15-verso
    - Note: [moved to WWI correspondence] Dear Mr Thomas (letter to L.T. from soldier at the front), 16
    - Note: [moved to World War I\Scrapbooks\Scrapbook I: Jerusalem] A Palestine officer as returned to England with three of the most remarkable flags of the whole war, 17
    - Note: Letter authenticating flags, 18
    - White flag used for Jerusalem surrender, 19
    - Headquarters flag, Emir Faisal, Damascus, Oct 3 1918, 20
    - Verso: Headquarters flag, Emir Faisal, Damascus, Oct 3 1918, 20-verso
    - Turkish flag placed on the Tomb of Saladin by Kaiser Wilhelm, 1898. Removed by order of Emir Faisal, 21
    - Verso: Turkish flag placed on the Tomb of Saladin by Kaiser Wilhelm, 1898. Removed by order of Emir Faisal, 21-verso
    - American on left in Kakai. French officer in horizon blue. Canadian in auto dressed in a yellowish uniform. All the Amaamites' faces are a jaundice-yellow hue from working in picric acid., 22
    - Verso: American on left in Kakai. French officer in horizon blue. Canadian in auto dressed in a yellowish uniform. All the Amaamites' faces are a jaundice-yellow hue from working in picric acid., 22-verso
    - [Aerial view of (?)], 23
    - [People standing in a cobblestone street], 24
    - [A large group of men eating], 25
    - [Large group of men on ship deck], 26
    - [Crowded ship decks], 27
    - [View of the city (location?)], 28
    - [Men on a ship], 29
    - Oct 11., 30
    - Dr. Powell [?], 31
    - Verso: Dr. Powell [?], 31-verso
    - [Dr. Powell (?)], 32
    - [Dr. Powell (?)], 33
    - The railroad that was built, 34
    - Verso: The railroad that was built, 34-verso
    - [Elaborate head-gear], 35
    - [Group of nine men (location?), 36